Guide to the Richard W. Lyman Personal Papers SC0562
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2014-099
  - Correspondence
    - Rosenzweig, Robert, 1990-2011 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Rudenstine, Neil L., 1991-1998 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Rurup, Reinhard, 1989-1991 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - R, 1989-2011 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Salamon, Lester M., 1988-1992 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Sanders, Timothy D., 1997-1998 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Sanchez, Jayne, 1996-2001 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Schauffler, Peter, 1991-2011 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Schneider, Stephen, 1990-1991 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Scott, Anne Firor, 1992-2008 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Scully, John, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Shultz, George P., 1988-1991 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Simmons, Adele, 1989-1994 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Smith, Joel P., 1993-2000 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Smith, Palmer, 1992-2004 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Spita, Lewis W., 1989-2000 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Stanley, Gary, 1994-2009 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Stanksy, Peter, 1989-2005 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Stone William E., 1992-2010 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Strauss, John C., 1996 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Strauss, Jon & Jean, 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Streit, Arnice, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Stephenson, Donald & Joy, 2000-2009 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Sym, Toni, 1992-1993 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - S (1/3), 1994-2011 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - S (2/3), 1991-1999 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - S (3/3), 1988-1990 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Tanner, Estelle N. (1/2), 1994-2001 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Tanner, Estelle N. (2/2), 1997-2004 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Taubman, Phillip, 2000-2008 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Taylor, J. Stephen, 1992-1998 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Thurber, James, 1989-1990 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Tooley, Reva and William, 1990-1991 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Tokinoya, Atsushi (Consul General of Japan), 1990-1991 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Trow, Martin, 1996-2006 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Tyack, David, 1995-2000 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - T, 1990-2006 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Ulnew, Consul Gen. Dag Mork, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - U, 1989-1999 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Von Schlegell, Abbie J., 1998-2006 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - V, 1989-1999 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Ware, James, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Waters, Robert, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Watkins, Diana, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Webb, Eugene J., 1989-1995 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Weiss, Daniel, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - White, Pat, 1996-2004 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Wildavsky, Aaron, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Wilkinson, Glenn, 2002-2003 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Willrich, Mason, 1989-1996 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Winfrey, Claire & Ian, 1994-2011 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Woolf, Pat (Writings), 1981, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Woolf, Pat, 1995-2010 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Wyman, Willard, 1993-2009 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - W, 1988-2011 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - X, Y, Z, 1988-2004 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - L, 1989-2007 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Naimark, Norman (CREES), 1989 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Nakashima, Erin, 1991-1992 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Powell, Barbara Lucking, 1993-1999 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Presley, Betsey, 1993-2005 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Prewitt, Kenneth, 1996-2009 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - P, 1988-2011 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Q, 1992 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Rabin - Liebowitz, 1990 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Raisan, John, 1993-1996 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Ravitch, Diane, 1989-1993 (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Rice, Condi, 1991-1994 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Riesman, David, 1992-1996 (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Roge, Pernille, 2007 (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Roberts, Myron, 1995-2001 (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Rosamond, Frances, 1996-1997 (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1997-2010 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Stanford Correspondence, 1992-2011 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Rolodex - Address Book (Box 76)
    - Rolodex - Address Book (Box 80)
  - Subject Files (Alphabetical)
    - Accountability Addresses, 1995-1996 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Aid to Artisans, 1992-2006 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Alumni Association, 1997-2007 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences: Nominations, etc., 1989-2006 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1998-2009 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - American Assembly, 1993-1997 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - AARR, 2000-2003 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - AAHE (American Association for Higher Education), 1996-2003 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - ACLS (American Council of Learned Socities), 1994 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - AHA (American Historical Association), 2000-2006 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - American Leadership Forum, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - American Philosophical Society (1/2), 1998-2003 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - American Philosophical Society (2/2), 2001-2009 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Association of American Universities, 1992-1995 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - The American Assembly, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - ARNOVA (Association for Research on Nonprofit Organizations and Voluntary Action), 1995 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - American Alliance for Rights and Responsibilities, 1993-1997 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Bacon House Committee, 1998 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Board of Trustees (Stanford), 1989-2006 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - CAFLIS (Coalition for Advancement of Foreign Languages and International Studies), 1989-1990 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Canadian Studies - Trudeau Visit, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Carnegie Commission: Preventing Deadly Conflict, 1994-2001 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Carnegie Corporation of NY, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - CFAT (Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching), 1996-2001 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Casper Inauguration, 1992 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Centennial Green, 1992 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - CCSRE (Center for Comparative Studies in Race and Ethnicity) (1/3), 1999-2001 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - CCSRE (2/3), 2001-2002 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - CCSRE (3/3), 2001-2005 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Chapman University, 2000 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - CISP (California International Studies Project), 1992-1995 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Commencement (Stanford University), 1993-2002 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Center for Study of Philosophy, 1992 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Committee on the Constitutional System (1/3), 1993-2002 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Committee on the Constitutional System (2/3), 1996-2006 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Committee on the Constitutional System (3/3), 2001-2006 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Commonwealth Club, 1997-2009 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Computer Information, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Council on Foreign Relations (1/2), 1997-2008 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Council on Foreign Relations (2/2), 1989-2009 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - COFHE (1/4), 1989-1991 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - COFHE (2/4), 1992-1999 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - COFHE (3/4), 1992-1993 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - COFHE (4/4), 1990-1994 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - COFHE - International Challenges for AMerican Higher Education, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Council on Foundations, 1996-2007 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - CREES (Center for Russian and Eastern European Studies), 1992 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Cuthbertson Award, 1993-1995 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Dinkelspiel Award, 1993 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Directories, 1991-1995 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - The Economist, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Education Commission of the States, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Emeritus Council, 2004-2006 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Encina Foundation, 1989-1992 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Faculty Club, 1993-1996 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Fallen Leaf, 1995 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Fellowship Forum, 2006 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Foundation Accountability Survey, 2002 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Friends of Stanford String Quartet, 1990-1996 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Trip to Hamden Hall Day School, 2011 May (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Hamden Hall School, 1992-2010 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Harvard Club of NY, 1991-2011 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Harvard, 2011 May (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Harvard University, 2002-2011 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Higher Education Policy Institute, 1996-1997 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - History Department, 1991-2002 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - History Department, 1990-1991 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - History Department, 1988-1990 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Hoover Institution, 1998 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Independent Sector Trip - LA, 1999 Oct 24-26 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Independent Sector, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Independent Sector - Membership Drive, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Independent Sector, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Independent Sector: Committee on Research, 1992-1995 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Independent Sector Past Chairs' Letter, 1999 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Independent Sector: Misc., 1992-1999 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Independent Sector Task Force on Accountability, 1999 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Independent Sector: Misc., 1995 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Independent Sector: Misc., 1992-1993 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - IPDO (International Program Development Office) - Washington State University, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Internationalizing U.S. Universities - Conference Proceedings, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Independent Sector, 1993 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Independent Sector: Misc, 1995-1996 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Independent Sector, 1994 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Independent Sector, 2000 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Lyman: Letters to Editors, etc. (1/2), 1990-2008 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Lyman: Letters to Editors, etc. (2/2), 2001-2006 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Lyman: Humanities Commission materials to take to the RF, 1977 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Lyman: Articles by RWL in The Economist (1/2), 1953-1958 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Lyman: Economist Articles (2/2), 1953-1960 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Lyman, Jing, 1988-2004 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Lyman, RW - Brief Biography, 2004-2009 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Lexia Exchange International, 1994-1996 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Lieberman Festschrift, 1994-1996 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Leah Kaplan Lecture, 1993 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Lexia, 1995 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - ISPAA, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Irvine Foundation, 1989-1998 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Irvine Group (1/2), 1988-1989 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Irvine Group (2/2), 1991-1992 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Jossey-Bass, Inc., Publishers, 1989-1990 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Irvine Group Task Force - Intercollegiate Athletics, 1990-1991 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - IIS and TIAA/CREF, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - IIS (Institute for International Studies) (1/2), 1989-1991 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - IIS (2/2), 1990-1999 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Institute of Current World Affairs, 1998-2006 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Institute of the Americas, 2000 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Institute for the Humanities and Sciences, 1989-2003 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - International Museum of Women, 2000-2001 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Indirect Cost Crisis, 1991-1994 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Independent Sector, 1990-1991 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - London School of Economics, 1992-2005 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Student Movements: A Five Country Comparison (Draft) by Andrew G. Caranfil, 1971 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Symposium on Measuring Institutional Performance, 1992 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Public Policy for Graduate Education (Draft) by RM Rosenzweig, undated (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Hollowed Collegiality: Implications for Teaching Quality - discussion paper by Massy, Wilger and Colbeck, 1994 February (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - A Utility Model for Teaching Load Decisions in Academic Departments - discussion paper by Massy and Zemsky, 1993 December (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Balancing Values and Market Forces: Perspectives on Resource Allocation - discussion paper by Massy, 1994 April (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Cream of the Crop: The Impact of Elite Education on the Decade After College - final chapter, 1994 March (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - National Policy and Higher Education - prepublication copy, 1973 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Lyman, RW: Talk, 1995 May (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Lyman: CCRI Talk, 1996 Nov 12 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Finberg Panel, 1996 Nov 6 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Lyman: Sr. Ctr. Talk, 1997 Nov 17 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Lyman: Marketplace (KOED), 1989 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Lyman, Richard: Photographs, 1980-2000 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Lyman Speech Texts (1/2), 1991-2009 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Lyman Speech Texts (2/2), 1992-2004 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - JFK Library and Museum, 1999-2004 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Lyman: Aborted Trip, 2004 April (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Lyman - 70th Birthday, 1993 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Lyman: 80th Birthday, 2003-2004 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Lyman: Daniel M. Bryan, 1999-2002 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Lyman, Richard - Personal (1/4), 1988-1990 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Lyman, Richard - Personal (2/4), 1987-1990 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Lyman, Richard - Personal (3/4), 1992-1998 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Lyman, Richard - personal (4/4), 1989-2011 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Lyman Book: Stanford in Turmoil, 1989-2007 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - National Committee on US and China Relations, 1995-2009 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - NCPI (National Center for Postsecondary Improvement), 2002 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - National Center for Public Policy and Higher Education, 1998 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - National Center for Victims of Crime, undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - National Humanities Center, 2001-2004 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Lyman: Meyerson Book Chapter, 1994 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Stanford in Berlin, 1991 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - NEH (National Endowment for the Humanities), 1995-2000 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - National Foreign Language Center, 1989 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - National Humanities Alliance, 1986-2003 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper Releases and Clippings, 1989 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - National Association of Scholars, 1988-1989 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Ombudsman, 1969-1971 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Pacific Council on International Policy, 1996-2004 (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - Planned Parenthood: Honorary Committee of Santa Clara and San Benito Counties, 1992 (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - President's Scholars, 1996 (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - Research and Scholarship at Stanford, 1991-1993 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Publications, 1988-1989 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Princeton Conference on Higher Education, 1996 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Princeton Conference on Higher Education, 1996 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Public Policy Institute of CA, 1999-2008 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Independent Sector - Memorandum, 1999 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - RLG (Research Library Group) - General File, 1990-2002 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Rockefeller Correspondence (1/4), 1989-2000 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Rockefeller (2/4), 1994-1998 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Rockefeller (3/4), 1999-2005 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Rockefeller (4/4), 2004-2006 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Royal Historical Society, 1991-2009 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - S.F. Committee on Foreign Relations, 1994-1996 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Save the Cookbook, 2006 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Stanford Daily, 1992-2000 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Speech Material - History of Stanford, 1993 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Stanford Humanities and Sciences, 2000-2001 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Stanford Budgets, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Shawnee Mission Public School, 1991 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Southern California Association for Philanthropy, 1998 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Standard Reply to Searches, 1988 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Stanford Libraries, 1999-2006 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Stanford Institute for Higher Education Research, 1991 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Stanford Miscellaneous (1/3), 1990-2002 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Stanford Miscellaneous (2/3), 1998-2002 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Stanford Miscellaneous (3/3), 2005-2011 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - Stanford Review, 1994-1995 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Sand Hill Road, 1997 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Stanford "Think Again", 2001-2002 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - SUSE (Stanford University School of Education), 1992-2004 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - SUSE - Expense Reports, 1991-2009 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - SUSE, Friends Of, 1993-2004 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Stanford University Press, 1992-2009 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Swarthmore College, 1992-2009 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Swarthmore Panel, 1992 June (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Worchester Polytechnic Institute, 1989-2008 (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - University Fellows, 1995-1997 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - WASC (Western Association of Schools and Colleges), 1989-1999 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Wheaton College, 1975, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Who's Who In America, 1998-2002 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - World Affairs Council, 1995-2006 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - World Forum of Silicon Valley, 1992-1997 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Yale, 2002-2003 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - IBM Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - IBM Correspondence, 1990 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - IBM Correspondence, 1991 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - IBM Correspondence, 1992 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - IBM Proxy Materials, 1992-1993 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - IBM Consultancy, 1993 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - IBM, 1987 Jan-June (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - IBM, 1987 July-Dec (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - IBM, 1991 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - IBM - DIrector's Questionnaire for Proxy Statement, 1980-1988 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - IBM- Top Security Clearance, 1986 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - IBM - Board of Directors, 1978-1979 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - IBM Audit/IBM Board - Armonk, NY, 1986 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - IBM - Including newspaper clippings re' pull out of South Africa, 1986 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - IBM Audit Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - IBM Personnel, 1993 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - IBM Board Meeting, 1992-1993 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - IBM Directorship, 1980-1981 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - IBM Complaints (1/2), 1993 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - IBM Complaints (2/2), 1993 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - IBM Complaints, 1992 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - IBM Clippings and Releases, 1991-1993 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - IBM, 1982-1983 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - IBM, 1983 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - IBM, 1984 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - IBM, 1986 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - IBM, 1988-1989 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - IBM - Expense Reports, 1988-1993 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Current Trip, 1990-1991 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Chase Expense Reports, 1989-1991 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - California State Automobile Association (AAA), 1980 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Christmas, 1995 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Airline General Info, undated (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - CIV: Printed Matter, 1996-1998 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Chase Manhattan Correspondence, 1982-1990 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Chase Officer Guests - Board Luncheon, 1987 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Chase Officer Guests Board Luncheon, 1987 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors, 1981 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Chase Manhattan, 1989-1992 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - CLAS, 1982-1991 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - CMB Board, 1991 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Chase Manhattan Bank, 1990-1994 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - The British Labour Party and the Russian Revolutions by Andrew A. Wood, 2007 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Chase Manhattan, 2000 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - American Council on Education- 57th annual meeting, 1974 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Various articles and Papers (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Lyman, Richard - Curriculum Vitae (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - The Enterprise Foundation, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - Channing House Strategic Plan, 2003 (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - S.U. Archives - ESL Oral History Project, 1980 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Lyman, Elizabeth (Jing) Biography, 1975-1981 (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - The Enterprise Foundation, circa 2003 (Box 70, Folder 16)
    - Assorted Organization Files, 2003 (Box 70, Folder 17)
  - Lectures
    - Special Lectures, 1974 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Special Lectures, 1975 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Special Lectures, 1976 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Special Lectures, 1977 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Special Lectures, 1978 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Special Lectures, 1952-1969 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Special Lectures, 1971 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Special Lectures, 1972 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Special Lectures, 1973 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Speeches (by others), 1982 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Special Lectures, 1970 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Philanthropy
    - RWL Charitable - Enterprise, 1996 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - RWL Charitable - AARP, 1996 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - RWL Charitable, 1996 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - RWL Charitable - AARR, 1996 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - RWL Charitable - AGB, 1996 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - ESL Charitable - Expenses, 1997 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - ESL Charitable - ALF, 1997 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - ESL Charitable - Enterprise, 1997 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - RWL Charitable - AGB, 1997 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - RWL Charitable - CCI, 1997 (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - RWL Charitable, 1997 (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - RWL Charitable, 1998 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - RWL Charitable - CCI, 1998 (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - ESL Charitable - Expenses, 1998 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - ESL Charitable - Academy of Leadership, 1998 (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - ESL Charitable - ALF, 1998 (Box 69, Folder 16)
    - ESL Charitable - Enterprise, 1998 (Box 69, Folder 17)
    - ESL Charitable - Bus. Income, 1998 (Box 69, Folder 18)
    - RWL Reimbursements, 1998 (Box 69, Folder 19)
    - RWL Charitable, 1999 (Box 69, Folder 20)
    - RWL Charitable - CCI, 1999 (Box 69, Folder 21)
    - ESL Charitable Expense Folders, 1999 (Box 69, Folder 22)
    - ESL Charitable - Academy of Leadership, 1999 (Box 69, Folder 23)
    - ESL Charitable -ALF, 1999 (Box 69, Folder 24)
    - ESL Charitable - Enterprise, 1999 (Box 69, Folder 25)
    - ESL Charitable - Expense Folder, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 26)
    - ESL Charitable - ALF-N, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 27)
    - ESL Charitable - Enterprise, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 28)
    - ESL Charitable - Academy of Leadership, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 29)
    - RWL Charitable, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 30)
    - RWL Charitable - CCI, 2000 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - ESL Charitable, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Charitable - Enterprise, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - RWL Charitable, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - RWL Charitable - CCI, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - ESL Charitable, 2003 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - ESL Charitable - Enterprise, 2003 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - RWL Charitable, 2003 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - ESL Charitable - Enterprise, 2004 (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - ESL Charitable Expenses, 1996 (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - Research and Writing
    - Modern Britain I (Box 20)
    - Modern Britain I & II (Box 21)
    - Modern Britain II & III (Box 22)
    - Modern Britain IV - Medieval Tudor - Stewart (Box 23)
    - Medieval Tudor - Stewart (Box 24)
    - Modern Britain - Bibliographical Key Notecards (1/3) (Box 25)
    - Modern Britain - Bibliographical Key Notecards (2/3) (Box 26)
    - Modern Britain - Bibliographical Key Notecards (3/3) (Box 27)
    - Economist, circa 1958 (Box 28)
    - European Labor and Socialist Movements (Box 29)
    - British Empire - Others (1/2) (Box 30)
    - British Empire - Others (2/2) (Box 31)
    - JRM Notes and Bibliography (Box 32)
    - Leadership and Ambiguity: The American College President by Cohen and March, 1972 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Stanford In Turmoil - Draft/Notes - Chap. 1-3, circa 2009 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Stanford In Turmoil - Draft/Notes - Chap. 4-8, circa 2009 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Stanford In Turmoil - Draft/Notes - Chap. 9, circa 2009 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Lessons Learned Manuscript by W.G. Bowen, 2010 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Various Writings, 1979-1989 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Politics, 1990-1992 (Box 71, Folder 1)